Sincro: wyxchari
海上救援队报告说没有找到，先生
Negative report from Air Sea Rescue, sir.
但有两架飞机掉了，肯定会有残骸的痕迹啊
But with two aircraft ditching,
there must be some signs of wreckage.
你为什么觉得变色龙的飞机是坠落到海里了？
Why do you think the Chameleon plane
crashed into the sea?
因为它从我们的雷达屏幕上消失了！
Because it disappeared off our radar screen!
但它一开始是静止没动！
But it stood still first!
因为它肯定是跟空军的飞机撞上了，然后掉落下去
Because it must have collided with
the RAF plane and dropped like a stone.
你为什么会这么想
Why do you think that?
要知道，当一架飞机像那样在雷达上静止不动
You see, when a plane on that radar
appears to stand still,
那么它事实上就是直线下落了
it is in point of fact dropping straight down.
- 直线上升怎么样？  - 噢，我亲爱的博士
- What about straight up? - Oh my dear Doctor!
要能像那样跑出我们雷达的范围
To get above our radar umbrella like that
它必须垂直爬上达到100英里高
it would have to climb vertically
until it was a hundred miles high.
那该死的高度就是外太空了
The darned thing would be in outer space.
正是这个！
Exactly!
那架派来跟踪我们的飞机，咱们要摧毁它吗？
That plane they sent to follow us.
Should we have destroyed it?
他们的玩具飞机，我们可以消灭他们一个中队
We could eliminate a whole squadron of their toy planes
而他们一点都够不着我们
and they'd never get on to us.
他们的脑子应付不了这样的行动
Their minds can't cope with an operation like this.
要记得我们总监的教导：地球人的智力
Remember the teaching of our Director -
the intelligence of Earth people
只跟我们星球的动物差不多
is comparable only to that of animals on our planet.
我就说我漏掉了一个，还在想你到底哪儿去了
I thought I'd missed one of you.
I wondered what happened to you.
- 你对他们做什么了？  - 关上抽屉
- What have you done to them?!
- Close that drawer.
不... 不...不要。别碰我
No... No... Don't. leave me.
好，谢谢你
Right, thank you.
海上救援队说他们还在搜索，但仍然没有任何痕迹
Air Sea Rescue say they're still searching
but there's no trace yet.
总指挥
Commandant.
我知道了。飞行员成功逃生了吗？
I see - did the pilot managed to bail out?
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
他们发现了空军飞机的残骸
They've found the remains of that RAF plane.
飞行员已经被电死了
The pilot had been electrocuted.
你还觉得这些人是来自地球？
Do you still think these people are from Earth?
我不知道，博士。我不知道该怎么思考了
I don't know, Doctor.
I just don't know what to think.
但凡有那么一丝确凿的证据就好了
If only there was one solid piece of evidence.
我觉得证据正好进来了！
I think it's just come in!
你介意我去盘问他吗？
Do you mind if I question him?//
我想我知道怎么撬开他的嘴
I think I know how to make him talk.
你知道这是什么东西，对吧？
You know what this is, don't you?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.//
噢，我觉得你知道。把你的袖子卷起来
Oh I think you do.
Roll up your sleeve.
我必须得听他的吗，先生？
Do I have to take orders from him, sir?
我觉得应该解释一下，博士
I think perhaps you should explain, Doctor.
毕竟呢，这个人是为我工作的
After all, this man is working for me.
只是你觉得他在为你工作！
You only think he's working for you!
总指挥，你的人员正在被系统性地替换掉
Commandant, your personnel
are being systematically replaced.
而这就是他们替换的方法
And this is how they're doing it.
这人不是 Meadows, 只是看起来像 Meadows
This is not Meadows, it only looks like Meadows.
而他的一个胳膊上带着一个这样的东西
He's wearing one of these things on his arm.
那好吧，按他说的做
Very well, do as he asks.
- 但是先生，这太荒谬了 - 我们都得为这事出力
- But sir, this is ridiculous...
- We all have to help in this
Meadows, 卷起你的袖子
Meadows. Roll up your sleeve.
拦住他！
STOP HIM!
把他弄到椅子上
Now get him in this chair.
Jean，叫警察
Jean, send for the police.
好了，博士，开始吧
All right Doctor, go ahead!
卷起他的左袖
Roll up his left sleeve.
准备好了，现在开始
There we are. Now then.
如果我转动这里面一个旋钮，会怎样？
What happens if I were to turn one of these?
别碰它！
Don't touch it!
啊，我明白了。好
Ah, I see. Right.
那么现在，你得回答我所有的问题了
Now then, you are going to answer all my questions.
而作为回报，我承诺不会伤害你
And in return, I promise no harm will come to you.
- 你明白了吗？  - 好吧
- Do you understand?   - All right.
你们的飞机把所有的乘客带到哪里去了？
Where are your planes taking all their passengers?
有一颗卫星，大约在150英里高空
There's a satellite,
about a hundred and fifty miles up.
你们为什么要绑架这些年轻人》
Why are you abducting all these young people?
我们的星球发生了一场大灾难，一次巨大的爆炸
We had a catastrophe on our planet.
A gigantic explosion.
如你所见，我们已经失去了自己的身份
As you've seen, we have lost our identities.//
我们的人要灭亡了！
My people are dying out!
但我们的人对你们有什么用？
But what use would our people be to you?
我们的科学家研究出来一个方法
Our scientists devised a process...
可以让我们得到另外一种生物的形体
so that we could take on the
physical characterises of another being.
而这就是这种方法的其中一步？
This is part of the process?
是，这就是为什么你不能碰那个
Yes, that's why you mustn't touch it.
你们打算绑架多少年轻人？
How many of these young people
do you hope to abduct?
这一次 - 四万
This time - Fifty thousand.
- 四万！  - 那个卫星有多大？
- Fifty thousand! - How large is this satellite?
在我们的飞机上，这些乘客会被缩小
On the journey in our planes,
the passengers are miniaturised.
我明白了。你们有多少人现在在盖特威克机场？
I see. How many of your people
are working here at Gatwick Airport?
我不知道
I don't know.//
这是真的，我跟你说，我不知道
That's the truth, I tell you. I don't know.
好吧。那我们的人怎么样了？
Very well. What happens to the people//
我们那些被换到身份的人，那些原身？
whose identities have been taken over, the originals?
他们在机场某个地方，我...我不知道具体在哪里
They're somewhere in the Airport,
I... I don't know exactly where.
我要把这个地方翻个底朝天，来找到他们
I'll have the whole place
torn to pieces to find them.
- 不，你不能去找他们  - 为什么不能？
- No, you mustn't find them. -  Why not?
你们...不能去，就是不能去
You... you mustn't, that's all.
因为如果我们真找到他们，就会在他们胳膊上找到这个，嗯？
Because if we do find them
we'll find one of these on their arms, eh?
而如果我们卸下它，就会有可怕的事情发生在你们身上？
And if we remove it,
something terrible will happen to you?
是的
Yes.
如果你们必须换回来怎么办？
What if you have to change back?
哦，那可以实现，但需要机器
Well, that can be done, but with the machine.
- 医护中心的那个机器？  - 对
- The machine in the Medical Centre?  - Yes.
我们谁也不知道我们的原身在哪里，除了那个护士
None of us know where our own originals are.
Except that Nurse.
- 护士？她什么情况？  - 噢，她可真狡猾
- Nurse? What about her?  - Oh she was cunning.
- 她把她的原身带在身边的  - 在哪里？
- She's got her own original with her.
- Where is it?
- 我不知道  - 我觉得你知道
- I don't know.  - I think you do know.
- 现在，你打算告诉我不？  - 在医护中心
- Now, are you going to tell me?
- It's in the Medical Centre.
很好，你得只给我看具体是哪里
Right. You're going to show me where it is.
我...我不敢，她会摧毁我的
I... I daren't. She'll have me destroyed.
你是打算合作呢，还是不合作？
Are you going to co-operate or are you not?
好吧，反正也没什么区别了
All right. It won't make any difference.
你再也见不到那五万个年轻人了！
You'll never see those
fifty thousand young people again!
我觉得我最好把他带过来 - 医护中心
I think I'd better take him down
there - the Medical Centre.
什么事
What is it?
那个女孩。我们怎么处置她？
This girl. What do we do with her?
我们需要把她用作原身
We need to use her as an original.
这样我们就可以安排一个我们的人
That way we can get one of our people//
在那个威胁我们的家伙身边
close to the man who is menacing us.
然后就可以杀了他
He will then be killed.
但 Blade 机长没打算带我们的人去地球...
But surely Captain Blade isn't
bringing any more of our people to Earth...
需要帮忙吗？
Can I help you?
带他进来
Bring him in.
恐怕我没搞懂
I'm afraid I don't understand.
我想你们俩有些共同点
I think you two have something in common.
那个人病了吗，警官？
Is this man ill, officer?
卷起你的袖子
Roll up your sleeves.
- 你在说些什么？  - 警官！
- What are you talking about?   - Officer!
请把你的手拿开
Please take your hands off me.
没问题。我想看的都看到了
Certainly. I've seen all I want to see.
我来拿这个，如果你不介意的话FIXME
I'll have that, if you don't mind!
好了，她的原身在哪里？
Now then, where is her original?
在那里面
It's in there.
- 你不能进里面去！  - 你还是愿意被毁灭喏？
- You can't go in there!
- Would you rather be destroyed?
看着他，警官
Keep an eye on her, officer.
把他带过来
Bring him along.
Sam! Sam, 你没事吧
Sam! Sam, are you all right?
- 你还好吧，Sam！  - 还好
- Are you all right Sam!  - Yes!
我还以为我完蛋了
I thought I was done for there.
- 手脚发麻  - 你运气好没有变得更严重
- Pins and needles...
- You're lucky it was no worse.
- 你在干什么？  - FIXME
- What are you doing? - Just checking up!
好了，护士的原身在哪里？
Now then, where is the Nurse's original?
在墙里某处的嵌板里面
It's in a panel in the wall somewhere.
开关在躺椅里面
The control's in the couch there.
好了，警官
All right, Officer.
见鬼诶，她还真在里面
Flipping heck! But she's in there!
你个叛徒！
You traitor!
小心!
Look out!
没事了 Sam，没事了
It's all right Sam. It's all right.
她消失了
She's vanished!
博士
Doctor.
把她放到那儿
Put her on here.
就这里吧
There we are.
- 会造成永久性损伤吗？  - 不会
- Will there be any permanent damage?  - No.
你可以把那个拿下来了
You can take that off now.
没事了，再过一两分钟你就完全没事了，来
It's all right. You'll be quite all right
in a few minutes. There.
博士，Jamie 他怎么了？
Doctor, what's happened to Jamie?
这些东西到底是做什么用的？FIXME
What on Earth are these doing here?
博士，上一次Jamie并不在柜台附近啊FIXME
Doctor, Jamie wasn't anywhere
near the kiosk the last time...
嘿你都没有在听，我觉得他们抓走了 Jamie!
Look you're not listening.
I think they've got Jamie!
- Jamie! 哪儿？  - 你应该知道的
- Jamie! Where?!  - Well you should know.
- 你让他顺走了我的机票？ - 顺走你的机票？
- You got him to pinch me ticket!
- Pinch your ticket?
为了阻止我去罗马
To stop me from going to Rome.
- 噢，你是说 Jamie  - 顶替了我
- Oh you mean Jamie...
- Has gone in my place.
先是 Polly 和 Ben，现在又是 Jamie
First Polly and Ben, and now Jamie.
我们不能再耽误时间了
We've no time to lose.
督察！
Inspector!
我们看看我能不能把你救出来
Let's see if I can get you out of there.
你怎么到这里来的？
How did you get here?
我...坐飞机来的，偷了别人的票
I... I came on the plane, stole someone's ticket.
你应该在路上就被小型化了
You ought to have been miniaturised on the journey.
小... 小型化？
Min... miniaturised?
被缩小了，就像柜子里所有这些年轻人这样
Reduced in size - like all the
youngsters in these cabins.
你没有吃喝什么吧？
Did you not have anything to eat or drink?
没有，我...觉得太难受了！
No, I... I felt too ill!
这就能解释了，那些食物是整个过程中的第一步
That explains it. The food is
the first part of the process.
督察，这是什么地方
Inspector, what is this place?
一颗卫星，Jamie。在太空的一艘飞船
A satellite, Jamie. A flying ship in space.
这些人来自另外的星球，看起来博士一直都是对的
These people are from another planet.
It seems the Doctor was right after all.
下面那些人有人相信他了吗？
Does anyone down there believe him yet?
噢，我...不太清楚。我...估计没有
Oh I... I'm not sure. I... I don't think so.
我估计这对他们来说太难以置信了
I suppose it is too much for them to believe.
但博士肯定已经让他们相信有事发生了吧？
But surely the Doctor's convinced them
that something is going on?
嗯，我觉得总指挥可能...
Aye, I think maybe the Commandant...
是的，Jamie
Yes, Jamie.
督察，你是逃出来的还是怎么的？
Inspector, have you escaped or something?
没谁能从这里逃走
No-one escapes from here.
但是那架飞到这里的飞机
But the plane that comes here.
它肯定会回到地球去，我们可以登上飞机
Well it must go back to Earth.
We could get on it!
最后一趟飞往地球的飞机已经走了
The last plane to Earth is leaving now.
他们只是回去接他们自己的人
They've just gone back to pick up their own people.
肯定博士会想到什么方法救我们
Surely the Doctor will think of some way of rescuing us.
这次不行了，Jamie
Not this time, Jamie.
这一次，他要对付的是比他还高级的脑子
This time, he's up against
a mind superior even to his.
总监的脑子
The mind of the Director.
你是说比博士还聪明？
You mean someone clever than the Doctor?
是负责这整个行动的人
The man in charge of this whole mission.
你似乎知道得不少，督察
You seem to know a lot about it, Inspector.
我当然知道，Jamie。我就是总监！
Of course I do, Jamie. I am the Director!
变色龙飞机就是在这个方位消失的
This is the bearing
where the Chameleon plane vanished.
我想知道它还会不会在这里出现
I want to know if it reappears there.//
他们下一个航班快到时间了
They've a flight due any minute.
很好先生
Very good sir.
博士，这些人事档案是怎么回事?
Now then Doctor, what's
all this about personnel files?
过来，我展示给你
Over here, I'll show you.
我在医疗中心找到这些的
I found these in the Medical Centre.
记录属于25个在这里工作的人
Records of twenty-five people who work here.
每一个都被变色龙给替换掉了
Each one of these has been taken over by Chameleons.
好，我会安排人在15分钟内将他们都抓起来！
Right. I'll have them all
under arrest within fifteen minutes!
Airport Police please.
请接机场警局
- 现在看看这个  - 这是什么？
- Now look at this.   - What is it?
变色龙的飞行排班表
Chameleon Air Schedules.
你看这里？他们这个季节的最后一班还有不到一个小时
You see here? Their last flight
of the season goes in an hour.
呃..请接 Reynolds 警司
Er.. Superintendent Reynolds please.
最后一班？那他们就不能抓了
The last flight? Well that's exactly
why they mustn't be arrested.
警司吗？我是总指挥
Superintendent? Commandant here.
- 你能听我说吗！  - 你能等一会儿吗？
- Will you please listen to me!
- Will you hold on a moment please?
- 这些人不能抓  - 为什么不能？
- These people must not be arrested. - Why not?
在外太空某个地方
Somewhere in outer space,
还有五万个年轻人，包括我的三个朋友
there are fifty thousand young people,
three of my friends amongst them,
我们得想办法把他们弄回来
and somehow we've got to bring them back.
我想登上这趟最后的航班
I want to get on this last flight,
也就意味着得让变色龙认为一切正常
which means the Chameleons must think that
everything is going according to plan.
总指挥？
Commandant?
Reynolds, 我回头再打给你
Reynolds, I'll call you back.
现在怎样？
Now what is it?
光点。突然凭空出现了，正朝这边过来！
This blip. It's just appeared out of nowhere
and it's coming this way!
好，跟踪住他们。可能是变色龙的飞机回来了
Right well keep tracking them.
It may be the Chameleon plane returning.
现在看这里，博士
Now look here, Doctor.
一直都在说登上那架飞机，但怎么做呢？
All very well talking about
getting on that plane, but how?
当前来看，你看起来像是一个叫 Meadows 的人
At the moment, you look like a man called Meadows.
你能移除这个身份，变成另外一个人吗？
Could you shed that identity
and become somebody else?
可以，我们中有些人被处理过两次
Yes. Yes, some of our people
have been processed twice.
好。那这样的话我就假装成一个变色龙，就这样上去
Good. Then in that case I shall pretend
I am a Chameleon, and get on board that way.
就算你登上那架飞机，你期望能做些什么呢？
But even if you get on that plane,
what do you hope to do?
我也不知道，得等到了卫星之后再说
I don't know until I get to the satellite...
而我只有一张牌可以打
and then I will have one card to play.
- 而这就取决于你了，总指挥  - 什么？
- And that's up to you Commandant. - What's that?
那些被变色龙顶替掉的人，那些真身
The people the Chameleons
have taken over, the originals,
被藏在盖特威克机场某个地方
are hidden somewhere here in Gatwick Airport.
- 你必须给找出来  - 当然，
- You have got to find them.
- Of course //
还得把那恐怖的东西从他们胳膊上卸下来
and get those fearful things off their arms.
不，不，不！用尽各种方法，找到他们
No, no, no! Find them, by all means,//
但不要去动胳膊上的护套
but don't tamper with those arm sheaths.
否则我们就没有了威胁
Otherwise we lose our one threat -//
the one thing I may be able to bargain with!
这可能是我能同他们讨价还价的唯一筹码！
我明白了。但我还是没明白你怎么能登上飞机
Yes I see that. But I still don't see
how you're going to get on that plane,
尤其是怎么能让他们相信，你是他们一员
let alone convince them
that you're one of their people.
那就得完全有赖于 Pinto 护士了
That will depend entirely on Nurse Pinto.
Jean，接警司 Reynolds
Jean, get onto Superintendent. Reynolds.
现在一切都清楚了吧？
Now is everything clear?
你确定你理解了我要让你做什么？
You're sure you understand
what I am asking you to do?
当然，但我们得为那些年轻人考虑
Yes, of course, but we've got to
think of those young people.
很是方便FIXME
How very convenient.
- 锁上门  - 别，别开枪！
- Lock the door.  - No, don't shoot!
这是 Meadows，他得重新处理一下
This is Meadows. He had to be re-processed.
为什么？
Why?
博士已经很怀疑这个 Meadows 了
The Doctor became too suspicious of me as Meadows.
我成功绑架了他。FIXME
I was able to kidnap him.
The rest is as you can see.
有点遗憾，本来有个人在航空控制塔台会很有用的
A pity. It was useful having
someone in Air Traffic Control.
当然我们掌控了博士的脑子也很不错
But then of course we have possession
of the Doctor's brain.
你觉得它会很有用吗？
You think that will be useful?
毫无疑问
Undoubtedly.
也就是说你会带我们到卫星上去？
That means that you'll be taking us
up to the satellite?
下一班我会带上所有人回到卫星
I am taking everybody back to
the satellite on the next plane.
这是最后一班了，这你肯定没忘吧
It's the last flight.
Surely you haven't forgotten that?
二次处理，太难记清楚细节了
The re-processing.
It's difficult to remember details.
是的，当然，我理解
Yes, of course, I understand.
你把他的真身怎么样了？
What have you done with his original?
在一个安全的地方
In a safe place.
跟其它的在一起
It should be with the others.
告诉具体是哪儿，我安排转过来
Tell me where that is
and I'll have it transferred.
没时间干这个了
There's no time for that now.
Jenkins 会帮你搞定出入境手续的
Jenkins will see you through Immigration.
我们会在15分钟后离开
We leave in fifteen minutes.
- 你觉得我们骗过他了吗？  - 说不好
- Do you think we convinced him?
- I don't know.
不管怎么说我们可以上飞机了，快点，我们别晚了
However we've got aboard that plane.
Come on, don't let's be late.
好的，谢谢
Right. Thank you.
是警方打来的，先生
That was the police, sir. //
他们说变色龙飞机的乘客已经在登机了
They say the passengers are now
boarding the Chameleon plane.
他们看到博士登上飞机了吗？
Did they see if the Doctor had got on board?
看到了，他和 Pinto 护士一起
Yes. He was with Nurse Pinto.
所有乘客都是成年人
All the passengers are adults
他们中的大多数人都是机场职员
and most of them have been
identified as airport personnel.
总指挥，变色龙飞机请求起飞
Commandant. Chameleon plane's requesting
clearance for start up.
好吧 Heslington, 程序照常，给他们许可
All right Heslington, normal procedure.
Give them clearance.
变色龙345，请准备
Chameleon Three-Four-Five,
stand by for start temperature...
是了，现在又是静止状态了
Yes. Now it's stationary.//
它肯定又在垂直爬升
It must be ascending vertically.
观点变弱了，先生
The blip's getting fainter, sir.
那就是说他已经超出了我们雷达的范围
That means he's rising above our radar umbrella.
啊，警司，真是你啊
Ah Superintendent, the very man.
光点消失了，先生
Blip's just gone, sir.
你看，Reynolds
Now look, Reynolds.
我们得把你那里的每一个人都派去搜寻
We've got to get every man
of your force on that search.
一刻也不能浪费。我们的时间不多了
There isn't a moment to lose.
Time's running out on us.
- 有消息吗？  - 没，看那个！
- Any luck?  - No. Look at that!
期望我的文件跟这一样整齐！
Wish my files were as neat as that!
你怎么样，柜台那里有什么？
How about you. What about the kiosk?
没什么，只有一些文件
Not much. Just a few papers.
唔，我们最好回到塔台去
Hmm... Oh we'd better get back
to Air Traffic Control then.
- 怎样？  - 就有一些文件，先生
- Well?  - Just a few papers sir.
也好，也许里面有点线索
Well, there might be a clue there.
总指挥，他们肯定是把他们放到某个地方了
Commandant, surely they'd
put them somewhere...
我的意思是，某个我们不会想到的地方
I mean, well somewhere we'd never think of.
我们得好好想想，Jean，不管它是哪儿
We've got to think of it, Jean, wherever it is.
博士还指望我们呢
The Doctor's relying on us.
成千上万人的性命有赖于我们找到那些真身，还得快！
Thousands of lives are depending on us
finding those originals - and quickly!
- 还有多久，博士？  - 我不知道
- How much longer, Doctor?  - I don't know.
我觉得我们快到了，别担心
I should think we're almost there. Don't worry.
等一下！
One moment!
由于我们的行动取得了圆满成功
Owing to the complete success of our operation,
我们的卫星上的生存空间不得不用于我们的货物
living space on our satellite
has had to be used for our... cargo.
所以，舱室会重新分配
Therefore, quarters will be re-allocated.
向住宿中心报告以获得指示
Report to the accommodation centre
for instructions.
你觉得他起疑心了没？
Do you think he's suspects?
说不好，我们先跟其他人走吧
I don't know. Let's follow the others.
你叫什么名字？
What is your name?
重试一遍，你叫什么名字？
Try again, What is your name?
Jamie​
Jamie.
你从哪里来？
Where do you come from?
从地球，一个叫做苏格兰的地方
From Earth, a place called Scotland.
非常好
Excellent.
- 总监  - 什么事？
- Director.  - What is it?
我们发现了两个冒牌货：博士和 Pinto 护士
We have found two impostors.
The Doctor and Nurse Pinto.
我请求授权我去消灭他们
I want permission to have them destroyed.
等一下，对于博士你都知道些什么？
One moment. What do you know about the Doctor?
他不是这个星球也不是这个时代的人
He is not of this Earth or of this century.
他穿越过时空
He has travelled through time and space.
他的知识甚至超过我们
His knowledge is even greater than ours.
总监，这个人对我们是个危险，必须被消灭
Director, this man is a danger to us,
he should be destroyed.
但我说他必须活着 - 不过是作为我们的人
And I say he must live - but as one of us.
你会后悔的
You will regret it.
你收到命令了，Blade 机长
You have your orders, Captain Blade.
我们现在怎么办？
What do we do now?
我们开溜，看看我们能后找到那些年轻人，快点
We slip away and see if we can
find these young people. Come on.
啊，Blade 机长，我们在按你的指令行事
Ah, Captain Blade,
we're carrying out your instructions.
我们在找住宿中心
We're looking for the accommodation centre.
我的指令对你们不适用
My instructions don't apply to you.
你们俩将不再需要居住空间了
You two won't be needing living space.